<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>OsmAnd blog</title>
<link>http://osmand.net/blog</link>
<description/>
<generator></generator>
<item>
<title>Christmas poins of interest in OsmAnd</title>
<link>osmand.net/blog?id=christmas_map</link>
<description>
<p>Christmas is coming! Dive into celebrations by visiting all the best holiday-related points of interest in your town. To view all attractions on the map, just go to Configure map menu - POI and select "Christmas".</p>
<div class="centeredimageblog">
<img src="images/blog/christmas_map/christmas_map2.jpg"/>
<img src="images/blog/christmas_map/christmas_map4.jpg"/>
<div style="clear:both;"></div>
</div>
<p>You'll see 5 types of POI:</p>
<ul>
 <li><b>Christmas event.</b> These points cover all types of Christmas celebrations, shows, etc.</li>
 <li><b>Christmas market.</b> Time to get some hot tea and ginger cookies. Use this POI to catch the most exciting markets around you.</li>
 <li><b>Christmas pyramid and Christmas tree</b> are also points you do not want to miss. Remember to take pictures.</li>
 <li><b>Christmas shop.</b> These POI will guide you to places where you can shop for the holiday.</li>
</ul>
<div class="centeredimageblog">
<img src="images/blog/christmas_map/christmas_map1.jpg"/>
<img src="images/blog/christmas_map/christmas_map1.jpg"/>
<div style="clear:both;"></div>
</div>
<p>Hint to mappers: add more Xmas objects to the map to help people enjoy the holiday even more!</p>
<h3>How to add Christmas POI to the map</h3>
<p>Ready to add Christmas-related POI to the map? There are some simple rules that will help you do that the best way possible. Tag the location, and do not forget about other details like the date when the attraction will be working. Follow the <b><a href="http://wiki.openstreetmap.org/wiki/Key:xmas:feature">link</a></b> to view a detailed guide to mapping Christmas POI. You'll also find a clear template there.</p>
<div class="centeredimageblog">
<img src="images/blog/christmas_map/christmas_map6.jpg"/>
<img src="images/blog/christmas_map/christmas_map7.jpg"/>
<img src="images/blog/christmas_map/christmas_map8.jpg"/>
<div style="clear:both;"></div>
</div>
<p>Remember, you can add POI to the map without leaving the app! Just to Plugins menu to activate the 'OSM editing' plugin, then return to the map, make a long press on a certain point and select 'Create POI'. Then you'll have to switch to the Advanced tab, enter the name of the POI and select its type (for example, Christmas tree) below the 'Name' line. After that, you'll be able to add any tags using the button 'Add tag'. For instance, you can write the tag 'xmas:feature' and in the 'value' field write 'tree'. This way, the people searching for Christmas trees nearby will see this one, as well.</p>
<p>Have questions? You can always contact us at support@osmand.net or join the discussion on <a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/osmand">OsmAnd's Google group</a>.</p>
</description>
</item>
	
<item>
<title>New OsmAnd Topo map style</title>
<link>http://osmand.net/blog?id=topo_style</link>
<description>
<p>Please welcome new OsmAnd Topo map style. If you are a hiker or a cyclist spending much time in the countryside, you are likely to appreciate the new style. It is designed to make your trips as convenient as possible while enjoying the nature.</p>
<img src="images/blog/topo/topo_1.jpg"/>
<img src="images/blog/topo/topo_2.jpg"/>
<p>Right from the beginning, you&amp;ll notice a comparatively high contrast of the map colors. The roads are displayed in orange shades with a clear and thick black border. This increases their visibility and improves map&amp;s legibility. Also, we&amp;ve transferred cycling and pedestrian routes from default OsmAnd style to make it even more convenient. </p>
<p>Contour lines are brown showing every 100m of altitude. You&amp;ll be able to see the names on such line presented in a dark color. The names won&amp;t resemble the shape of lines: such solution improves readability of information.</p>
<img src="images/blog/topo/topo_5.jpg"/>
<p>The ridges have black edges with nicks. The buildings are represented in solid black color. It reduces your chances to miss a shelter in a sparsely populated area.</p>
<img src="images/blog/topo/topo_3.jpg"/>
<img src="images/blog/topo/topo_4.jpg"/>
<p>The forests are painted in a brighter shade of green. Deep rivers and lakes have deep-colored edges, while smaller rivers and other waterways are dark blue. Railroads are black and all electric railways have cross strokes, the text is mainly black with white edges.</p>
<p>Also, some symbols are different in the topo style: &amp;surface integral rendering&amp; is made to conveniently show the surface information. You can add or remove this feature in Configure map - &amp;Details&amp; menu. The roads will be marked according to the scale presented below. Access restriction symbols have been made dark-red to prevent violation of private property or planning your route across a closed area. Spot obstacles are shown as dots on bigger scales.</p>
<p>Linear obstacles are represented as fine lines visible from zoom level 16 or from level 13 if you enable the &amp;More details&amp; option. You can enable it in Configure map - &amp;Details&amp; menu. Main landmarks are designed to be seen from higher scale levels.</p>

<img src="images/blog/topo/topo_6.jpg"/>
<p>Enjoy your travel with OsmAnd!</p>
</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>OsmAnd 2.4 released</title>
<link>http://osmand.net/blog?id=osmand-2-4-released</link>
<description>
<p>An OsmAnd update is here. We've introduced a new search interface and many fixes. Read on to find out all the details.</p>
<h2>New quick search</h2>
<p>A quick search was probably one of the most requested features we've received. A first version of it is included in this release. Now, you can enter almost any type of query, be it a type of POI, an address or even a link to the map and find it using the Search button on the map screen.</p>
<img src="images/blog/2.4/search_1.jpg"/>
<img src="images/blog/2.4/search_2.jpg"/>
<h2>Car audio system integration</h2>
<p>Now OsmAnd can be integrated into your car navigation system. Connect an Android device running OsmAnd via Bluetooth to a car stereo system which provides speakerphone functionality. If in OsmAnd you select Settings - General Settings - Voice guidance output - Phone call audio, OsmAnd will interrupt any music to play its navigation prompts.</p>
<img src="images/blog/2.4/voice_guidance_integration.jpg"/>
<h2>Helpful transport information</h2>
<p>In the previous OsmAnd release, we introduced transport stops information. In 2.4, this has been improved. Now, you can turn them on in Configure map - Transport - Transport stops, then tap on one and see all the routes on that stop. More to come, you can tap a route to view it on the map from start to end.</p>
<img src="images/blog/2.4/routes_1.png"/>
<img src="images/blog/2.4/routes_2.png"/>
<p>We reworked route guidance, voice prompting, and added new turn lane indication. The release also includes numerous fixes like improved storage management, etc. Besides that, some local languages like Sorbian have been added to the new release. Also, yu can now enjoy support of such language options as Spanish (American) and English (United Kingdom). They will be of best help as map languages in the regions to show you the geographical names in regional language. To set your chosen language as map language, please go to Configure map - Map language.</p>
<p>Hurry to update your OsmAnd today!</p>
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>OsmAnd API Demo</title>
<link>http://osmand.net/blog?id=api_demo</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 6 May 2016</pubDate>
<description>
<p>OsmAnd API Demo allows you to test integration with OsmAnd and functioning of the main features.</p>
<p>OsmAnd API features:</p>
<ul >
<li>Adding favorites and markers to the map</li>
<li>Creating audio/video/photo notes</li>
<li>Starting and stopping GPX track recording</li>
<li>Importing GPX tracks into OsmAnd and navigating along them</li>
<li>Navigation between locations</li>
</ul>
<img src="images/blog/api_demo_osmand/api_d1.jpg"/>
<img src="images/blog/api_demo_osmand/api_d2.jpg"/>
<p>More about features and how to work with them: <a href="https://github.com/osmandapp/osmand-api-demo">https://github.com/osmandapp/osmand-api-demo</a></p>

<p>To test OsmAnd API Demo options, you need to install one of <a href="http://osmand.net/help/changes.html">OsmAnd Maps versions</a>.</p>
</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>OSM Live</title>
<link>http://osmand.net/blog?id=osm-live</link>
<description>
<p>
Hi All,
<br/>
It&#39;s been about a week since we delivered OsmAnd 2.3 to more than half of our users. This release was mostly dedicated to OSM Live and we are very happy that today we have around 100 supporters and 100 mappers. Let's briefly iterate how it works.
</p>
<img src="images/blog/2.3/osm_live_1.png"/>
<br/>
<p>OsmAnd users pay in order to get hourly map updates. This money is split into 2 parts and one goes to OsmAnd developers while the other goes to mappers around the world. Today we've already processed three monthly payments started January 2016. We still add some funds to the mappers part, so the payouts look reasonable.</p>
<br/>
<p>From the beginning, we wanted to make the system as transparent as possible. So please find everything on the page <a data-gatag="osm_live" href="http://osmand.net/osm_live">http://osmand.net/osm_live</a>. Essentially, we are trying to build a crowdfunding (donation) for OSM and we want to use all modern technologies to make the process as much visible as possible. One of that technology is Bitcoin. Bitcoin lets us show how collected money is sent to mappers, for example, <a href="https://blockchain.info/tx-index/138988481">https://blockchain.info/tx-index/138988481</a>.</p>
<br/>
<p>After we launched OSM Live, many people supported the initiative, but they had some concerns and questions. This is why we decided to respond to them publicly so that everybody could find the answers.</p>
<h4>Financials</h4>
<ul >
	<li>Supporters can buy in-app only in 2 applications: OsmAnd Free and OsmAnd+ and only on Google Play platform.</li>
	<li>We plan to support direct donations to bitcoin address and different platforms but we focused first on the platform that has > 90 % of all our users, i.e. Google Play.</li>
	<li>The price for OsmAnd+ is around 1 EUR and for OsmAnd Free is 1.5 EUR. The prices are different because in OsmAnd Free all downloads will be enabled automatically for the subscription period, so in that case, there is no immediate need to buy OsmAnd+.</li>
	<li>Please keep in mind there are transactions costs between Supporter and Recipient. Google takes <b>30%</b> of every payment, Bitcoin processing fees are very small and about 0.5%. OsmAnd takes 30% but it is part of the contribution itself and enables hourly updates features.</li>
	<li>Please keep in mind that there are transactions costs between Supporter and Recipient. Google takes 30% of every payment, Bitcoin processing fees are very small - about 0.5%. OsmAnd takes 30% but it is part of the contribution itself and enables hourly updates features.</li>
	<li>We understand that OSM Live is not just a feature but a crowdfunding platform and one price doesn't fit all cases. So we plan to enable more in-app subscriptions and purchases in later releases.</li>
	<li>We've been also receiving questions on how to donate to OsmAnd team directly and we also plan to add a way to do that soon.</li>
</ul>
<h4>Mappers</h4>
<ul >
	<li>Important: OsmAnd doesn't store any OSM passwords on the website! You can double check the code <a href="https://github.com/osmandapp/osmandapp.github.io/blob/master/website/osm_live.php">here</a>. We are searching for a more convenient method and would like to switch to OAuth or just sending a private confirmation link/message to OSM user. There were discussions with contributors about it and we hope to get a pull-request with that code.</li>
	<li>In order to get a minimal payout, the mapper should make at least 3 changes (changesets) a month. That's not much and we think to increase that number to 5-6. You can see the according statistics on the first page <a data-gatag="osm_live" href="http://osmand.net/osm_live">OSM Live</a> that gives a threshold of 50% monthly contributors.</li>
	<li>All mappers are divided into 20 groups (worldwide) and 7 groups (each region). Based on the group, each mapper ends with a rank assigned. The 1st ranking is assigned to the group of people who did the most changes. We intentionally divided the users into groups so people from the first group wouldn't compete for the top 1 place and feel reasonable with assigned ranking.</li>
	<li>Each ranking is transformed into weight by simple formula Weight = Groups (20 or 7) + 1 - Rank. The total amount is divided equally with weight multiplier.</li>
	<li>We came up with the idea to have regional preferences and regional payouts for changes made in a specific region. So far it is pretty much equally distributed everywhere and doesn't give any reasonable effect in payout.</li>
	<li>There is a valid concern that some people could start making fake changesets in order to get higher in ranking. We think to start solving that issue when it becomes visible, today payouts are quite small and they are pretty much equal between registered contributors.</li>
</ul>
<h4>OSM Live updates</h4>
<p>OsmAnd hourly updates are still in Beta. Address incremental update is not supported and last minute we had to disable OSM Live for Routing. Mostly the issues are related to maps themselves and users don't need to update OsmAnd 2.3 but they require new maps.</p>
<ul >
<li>Please be aware of a serious possible issue with map rendering. It might become extremely slow or have diagonal lines (<a href="https://github.com/osmandapp/Osmand/issues/2398">1</a>, <a href="https://github.com/osmandapp/Osmand/issues/1843">2</a>). It is still not fixed and we plan to provide a fix with April OSM maps. Maps should be redownloaded. It is still not fixed and we plan to provide a fix with April OSM maps. Maps should be redownloaded.</li>
<li>Today we have around 4-5 hours delay after a change in OSM until the map will be available for downloads in OsmAnd. We plan to reduce to 15-20 minutes soon.</li>
<li>The delta maps are designed to work in a reasonable way for 5-6 months, so sometimes it is good to clean OSM Live and redownload the base map. In case of any unexpected rendering issues, please try to disable OSM Live first. The technology is still in Beta and will need some time to mature.</li>
</ul>
<br/>
<h4>Only together we can make OSM better.</h4>
</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>OsmAnd 2.3</title>
<link>http://osmand.net/blog?id=osmand-2-3-released</link>
<description>
<p>OsmAnd 2.3 is on its way! Get ready for a brand new route preparation interface, improved UI, and more. We also added a revolutionary feature for you to try.</p>
<h2>OSM Live Beta</h2>
<p>The most important and outstanding feature of the new release is OSM Live. It's the system that will encourage OSM mappers to update the information and will give you frequent updates (up to once an hour). You make a donation and receive the updates, 30% goes to the OsmAnd team and 70% is spread between OSM contributors who have registered in the OSM Live program. They are encouraged to make more updates and you get fresh and more detailed maps. Please read more and join here.</p>
<img src="images/blog/2.3/ver_2_3_9.jpg"/>
<img src="images/blog/2.3/ver_2_3_10.jpg"/>
<h2>New map markers interface</h2>
<p>Map markers are points you can add to the route or leave for future trips. Add them to the map to use for route preparation or save for future.</p>
<img src="images/blog/2.3/ver_2_3_11"/>
<img src="images/blog/2.3/ver_2_3_12"/>
<h2>General improvements</h2>
<p>Now, you'll see the address when you tap a location on the map. This makes map use even smoother. Besides that, text rendering throughout the application has become better.</p>
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>OsmAnd 2.2</title>
<link>http://osmand.net/blog?id=osmand-2-2-released</link>
<description>
<p>New OsmAnd 2.2 has been released. Fuller POI information, restructured downloads and a brand-new UI are some of the main things to see. Get the update now!</p>
<h2>Reworked context-sensitive UI</h2>
<p>OsmAnd has acquired a whole new context menu design that changes according to the content and the type of location you're working with. Now POI, Favorites and other types of locations get corresponding context menus to help you operate the app much easier. Also, you can now just tap on a region you need to download the map. This way, you'll get the map sections that you need much faster. More to come, you can enjoy amazing pull-up menus and a whole new Create POI interface.</p>
<img src="images/blog/2.2/ver_2_2_9.jpg"/>
<img src="images/blog/2.2/ver_2_2_17.jpg"/>
<h2>New Wikipedia data, downloads by country and much more complete data</h2>
<p>Now you can enter the name of the country and see all maps available for this particular location: the Standard map, Hillshade, Wikipedia data, Contour lines map and Roads-only map. This way, you'll see Wikipedia files as soon as you enter the country name. Besides that, the Wikipedia data has gotten fuller.</p>
<img src="images/blog/2.2/ver_2_2_2.jpg"/>
<img src="images/blog/2.2/ver_2_2_3.jpg"/>
<h2>New navigation interface</h2>
<p>You can build a route with all your waypoints or select to go right to the destination point. To do it, just tap the destination, and then press the blue navigation button.</p>
<img src="images/blog/2.2/ver_2_2_10.jpg"/>
<img src="images/blog/2.2/ver_2_2_18.jpg"/>
<h2>Reworked POI editing menu</h2>
<p>See new improvements in the POI editing section. You can now edit the points of interest you've created before committing them to the server. Also, the whole new Edit POI menu interface will help you add new points rapidly and manage them. Just don't forget to turn OSM Editing plugin on.</p>
<img src="images/blog/2.2/ver_2_2_8.jpg"/>
<img src="images/blog/2.2/ver_2_2_14.jpg"/>
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>OsmAnd 1.2.2 for iOS is now released</title>
<link>http://osmand.net/blog?id=osmand-ios-1.2.2-released</link>
<description>
<p>The new OsmAnd release has a list of new features that are waiting to be tried out. You can now use shading on the map to see the relief, plan trips and search for points of interest in a handy way. Let's get to details.</p>
<h2>POI on the map</h2>
<p>One of the significant steps forward is the ability to view POI on the map. From now on, you'll be able to view any points of interest as you enter the Search.</p>
<img src="images/blog/ios-1.2.2/ios_2_1_1_3.jpg"/>
<h2>Hillshade maps</h2>
<p>The OsmAnd iOS version now has the hillshade maps. Those are map layers visualizing the details of the terrain. The hillshade maps are available by country.</p>
<img src="images/blog/ios-1.2.2/ios_2_1_1_17.jpg"/>
<h2>Creating new trip</h2>
<p>You can now just enter the My trips menu, choose Create new trip and then add waypoints by making long taps. Add details to the waypoint, such as its name, color indicating this waypoint, its group (you can create a group of waypoints: work locations, favorite spots on town, etc.) and a description.</p>
<img src="images/blog/ios-1.2.2/ios_2_1_1_7.jpg"/>
<img src="images/blog/ios-1.2.2/ios_2_1_1_8.jpg"/>
<h2>Route preparation and viewing your trip</h2>
<p>You can choose to sort your waypoints using the route management menu. Just tap the blue toolbar, then swipe the waypoint you'd like to move higher on the list and tap the arrow icon. Activate or deativate waypoints to customize your route in this menu. Also, now you can add an endless number of waypoints.</p>
<h2>Navigation</h2>
<p>Now you can view waypoints or delete them by tapping on the upper toolbar and swiping to the left. Tap the arrow to unfold the full list and choose the point you need to get to in order to see the distance to it and view the location on map. Please note that the points are connected by straight lines and are meant to help you create a general understanding of the directions for your trip.  To mark it as visited, select the checkbox sign. Same checkboxes will be available as soon as you approach the waypoints.</p>
<img src="images/blog/ios-1.2.2/ios_2_1_1_13.jpg"/>
<h2>Improvement in POI search</h2>
<p>As you search for the points of interests, your previous destinations will be added to make searching even easier. The same applies to the favorites.</p>
<p>The new version also has lots of small improvements to make the user experience better. Go ahead and try out OsmAnd 1.2.2. <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/osmand-maps/id934850257?mt=8">Install!</a></p>
</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>OsmAnd 1.1.1. for iOS released</title>
<link>http://osmand.net/blog?id=osmand-ios-1.1.1-released</link>
<description>
<p>A new OsmAnd version for iOS is here! The update includes a convenient plugin, more improvements in the POI area and a nicer UI.</p>
<h2>Offline Contour Lines Maps</h2>
<p>This plugin, being much appreciated by Android users, is now available in the iOS version. It provides you with quite detail info on the terrain of a certain location and the heights. To get the plugin, just go to the in-app purchase area.</p>
<img class="leftimage" height="400" src="images/blog/ios-1.1.1/ios_1-1_14.png" alt="TODO"/>
<h2>POI improvements &amp; Wikipedia</h2>
<p>Now you can get even more detailed info about POI and use Wikipedia articles offline.</p>
<img src="images/blog/ios-1.1.1/ios_1-1_10.PNG" alt="Download contour lines &amp; wikipedia maps"/>
<img src="images/blog/ios-1.1.1/ios_1-1_7.PNG" alt="Wikipedia search"/>
<img src="images/blog/ios-1.1.1/ios_1-1_9.PNG" alt="Wikipedia article"/>
<h2>New trip recording features and UI advancements</h2>
<img class="leftimage" height="400" src="images/blog/ios-1.1.1/ios_1-1_5.PNG" alt="Add waypoints to recording track"/>
<p>You can add new waypoints to the track while recording it or do the same with a new track without recording. Also, you&#39;ll see UI amendments called to make the use of the app better.</p>
</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>5 years with OsmAnd!</title>
<link>http://osmand.net/blog?id=5_years</link>
<description>
<p>5 years with OsmAnd!</p>
<img src="5years_blog.png" />
<p>Hard to believe, but it' s been 5 years since OsmAnd app appeared in the market. To recap the highlights of our work so far, we decided to ask OsmAnd team members how do they feel about working here, why they chose to work on a navigation app and more.</p>
<br/>

<p>Viktor Shcherb, CEO</p>
<p><b>What does #osmandme mean to you?</b></p>
<p>First of all, it means the favorite map &amp; navigation tool. All the operations I do myself I do with OsmAnd. Before I had a navigation tool, I used paper maps for the most operations and I still love them. Nowadays, I can' t imagine my normal life without OsmAnd, it covers most of the aspects of outdoor activities: hiking, going to restaurant, tourism, boat trips, forest walks and, of course, car travels. Surprisingly, I read #osmandme as ' OSM and Me' and OsmAnd is a tool to use these features. I need to confess, I have a crazy idea to extend OsmAnd and use all the features that OSM data can provide). By the way, it was a conscious decision to put OSM in the name of the product. I believe in OSM and I would like to thank all OSM contributors.</p>
<p>Join special giveaways!</p>
<p>Head over to Facebook to win a unique app build with a feature our developers will introduce specially for you. Just write about your experience of using OsmAnd, tell us why you like the app or share a story about this application, use hashtag #osmandme and #osmandfive to join the giveaway. And don't forget to check out our twitter giveaway, too! Win Osmand+ app today. The celebration won't be the same without you, so join now!</p>
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 26 June 2015</pubDate>
</item>

<item>
<title>5 years with OsmAnd!</title>
<link>http://osmand.net/blog?id=5_years</link>
<description>
<p>Hard to believe, but it' s been 5 years since OsmAnd app appeared in the market. Read developers' interviews and join anniversary giveaways!</p>
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 26 June 2015</pubDate>
</item>

<item>
	
<title>OsmAnd 2.1</title>
<link>http://osmand.net/blog?id=osmand-osmand-2-1-released</link>
<description>
<p>OsmAnd 2.1 release is out! This time, we focused on improving POI search and making your trips even more interactive through new Wikipedia data sorted by country.</p>
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 June 2015</pubDate>
</item>

<item>
<title>OsmAnd 1.0.2 (iOS)</title>
<link>http://osmand.net/blog?id=osmand-ios-1.0.2</link>
<description>
	<p>We are glad to announce that iOS version of OsmAnd is becoming better over time. We put significant efforts and managed to finish lots of useful features in a short period of time. Here is the short list of achievements.</p>
<ul>
	<li>We significantly improved the responsiveness of the map interaction.</li>
	<li>OsmAnd Maps now is also available for iPad.</li>
	<li>We added translations to Russian, German, Danish, French, Spanish and other languages (thanks to our great community). </li>
	<li>Parking Position and Trip Recording addons were added to the application. Please feel free to use them without charge</li>
	<li>In the new version you will be able to search a location by simply put the url or enter the coordinantes in the search text box.</li>
	<li>And lots of other minor and useful improvements.</li>
</ul>
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 18:30:40 +0100</pubDate>
</item>


<item>
<title>OsmAnd 2.0</title>
<link>http://osmand.net/blog?id=osmand-2-0-released</link>
<description>
<p>We are glad to announce that OsmAnd 2.0 is coming to devices. We expect to finish the rollout on this week. This has been a while we had to admit that OsmAnd didn't follow the guidelines and had an inconsistent UI. This major release we fully focused to put the most trending UI, Material Design, in place. Meanwhile we considered dozens interactive patterns to improve the usability of various features in OsmAnd and came up with a Dashboard screen, which provides a balanced solution between Search &amp; Map display. Please help us by giving your feedback to make the product better.</p>
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2015 18:30:40 +0100</pubDate>
</item>


<item>
<title>OsmAnd for iPhone</title>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://osmand.net/blog?id=osmand-ios</guid>
<link>http://osmand.net/blog?id=osmand-ios</link>
<description>
<p>We are glad to announce that iPhone version of OsmAnd is released.</p>
<p>This version contains the most used functionality of Android version together with significantly improved user interface, which we believe is a good combination.</p>
			
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2015 12:30:40 +0100</pubDate>
</item>


<item>
<title>Nautical charts</title>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://osmand.net/blog?id=nautical-charts</guid>
<link>http://osmand.net/blog?id=nautical-charts</link>
<description>
<p>OsmAnd 2.0 is coming soon. One of the new features of the version will be Nautical Charts plugin.</p>
<p>Nautical Chart is a detailed graphical representation of oceans, seas, coastal areas and rivers.</p>
<p>Nautical Charts are made for people who drive any kind of vehicle on water: from professional sailors to people who rented a boat to make a tour over city canals. The charts can contain various information like sailing routes, navigation lights, dangerous areas, areas where it&apos;s allowed or not allowed to sail or dock, etc.</p>
<p>All the professional sailors are obliged to have official nautical charts on their ships. These charts are published by authorized agencies and cost quite some money. Agencies are investing a lot in keeping the charts up to date. They release updates for the charts on regular basis, but because of the fact that reviewing the information and processing the updates takes quite some time the nautical charts are never completely up-to-date. </p>
 <a href="http://osmand.net/blog?id=nautical-charts">Read more</a>
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 18:30:40 +0100</pubDate>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>

